A Guide to the Peter F. Geithner papers FA1408
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Professional and personal files, third run, 1982-2005; 5; 6.301 Cubic Feet 18 LTR size Hollinger boxes
  - Subject files, 1982-2005; 2; 1.71 Cubic Feet About 4.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    - K - Subjects, 1996-2003 (Box 127, Folder 1651-1652)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Vijay Kelkar; Joan Kaufman; William J. Klausner; Kusuma Snitwongse, and Korea.
    - L - Subjects, 1997-2004 (Box 127, Folder 1653)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Lu Mai; Land ownership in China; and Luo Xiaopeng.
    - M - Subjects, 1995-2004 (Box 127, Folder 1654-1655)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Shoma Munshi; Yan Mei; Ian Martin; and the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation.
    - N - Subjects, 1996-2003 (Box 127, Folder 1656)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: The National Committee on U.S.-China Relations (NCUSCR) and Narongchai Akrasanee.
    - O - Subjects, 1997-1999 (Box 127, Folder 1657)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Oxfam International and Oxfam America.
    - P - Subjects, 1996-2004 (Box 127, Folder 1658-1659)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: The Program for International Studies in Asia (PISA) and V. A. Pai Panandiker.
    - Q - Subjects, 1997-2004 (Box 128, Folder 1660)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Kevin F. F. Quigley and Maureen E. Quigley.
    - R - Subjects, 1996-2004 (Box 128, Folder 1661-1662)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Swati Ramanathan; Thomas G. Rawski; Delwin Roy; and Gowher Rizvi.
    - S - Subjects, 1996-2004 (Box 128, Folder 1663-1666)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: H.R.H. Princess Maha Chakri Sirindhorn of Thailand; Self-government; Sreekumar Siddique; Rosalia Sciortino; Somtow Sucharitkul; K. C. Sivaramakrishnan; South Asia; Mark Sidel; Anthony Saich; The Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences (SASS); The Social Science Research Council (SSRC).
    - T - Subjects, 1998-2005 (Box 128, Folder 1667)
      Separated Materials
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Taiwan and Anne Thurston.
    - U - Subjects, undated (Box 128, Folder 1668)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: U.S.-Japan relations.
    - V - Subjects, 2004-2005 (Box 128, Folder 1669)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Trina Vithayathil.
    - W - Subjects, 1996-2004 (Box 129, Folder 1670-1674)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Alyssa Worsham; Juliet Wu; Women In International Security (WIIS); The World Trade Organization (WTO); and Yoshiko Wakayama.
      Although distinct V and W subject files had been created and maintained in order to organize the records, there appears to be several topics starting with the letter V in the W subject file. These topics include: Vietnam; Verite Faculty Audits; Tom Veblen; and Toby Volkman.
    - X-Y-Z - Subjects, 2004 (Box 129, Folder 1675)
      Topics, organizations, and individuals featured prominently within the subject file include: Shirley Yue and Yunching Tseng.
  - Correspondence with individuals, 1995-2005; 3; .95 Cubic Feet About 2.5 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    Subseries contains a group of records organized by the names of individual correspondents with whom Peter F. Geithner communicated. Files were created for each correspondent or set of correspondents. However, files are not alphabetically arranged by the last name of the correspondent(s). Both professional and personal correspondence can be found within the subseries.
    Files contains material that was not produced or received by the correspondent identified in the file title. Instead, the identified correspondent was featured as the subject within correspondence between Geithner and another individual. In the case of the Phetkanha, Yui, 1998-1999 file (Folder 1712), the file only includes correspondence that references the identified correspondent and contains no correspondence created or received by Phetkanha.
    The subseries also holds some miscellaneous reports and papers that were inserted in between the subject files. The relationship between this content and the subject files is unclear.
    - Meyers, Kathrine, 1999-2005 (Box 129, Folder 1676-1678)
    - Husain, M.F., 1998-1999 (Box 129, Folder 1679)
    - Lees, Martin R., 1998-1999 (Box 129, Folder 1680-1681)
    - Meng, Sherry, 1998-1999 (Box 130, Folder 1682)
    - Edwards, Michael, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 1683)
    - Evans, Paul, 1998-2002 (Box 130, Folder 1684)
    - Evans, Paige, 1999-2000 (Box 130, Folder 1685)
    - Multiple correspondents, 1999-2003 (Box 130, Folder 1686)
    - Multiple correspondents, 1997-2004; File contains three still images. They are photographs of Yui Phetkanha in a Chanel campaign for the magazine, Vogue. They were attached to a couple of pieces of correspondence between Peter F. Geithner and Ivan Walsh. (Box 130, Folder 1687-1688)
    - Prasad, Jagdish (A. J. Prasad), 1995-1997 (Box 130, Folder 1689)
    - Allan, Sarah, 2000-2002 (Box 130, Folder 1690)
    - Chan, Ronnie C., 1998-2000 (Box 130, Folder 1691)
    - Chanda, Nayan, 2000-2003 (Box 130, Folder 1692)
    - Rizvi, Gowher, 1998-2002 (Box 130, Folder 1693)
    - Viraphol, Sarasin, 1999-2004 (Box 130, Folder 1694)
    - Sirindhorn, H.R.H. Princess Maha Chakri, 1999-2004; Some material was removed from the file during processing because of suspected mold growth. (Box 130, Folder 1695-1696)
    - H.R.H. Princess Maha Chakri Sirindhorn letter and postcard paintings, 2002; Item was removed from Sirindhorn, H.R.H Princess Maha Chakri correspondence file (Folder 1695) because of inactive mold growth. Item has been cleaned and placed in Mylar sleeves.It can be handled safely. Item was placed at end of collection for security of the item. (Box 144, Folder 1854)
    - Pitsuwan, Surin, 2003 (Box 130, Folder 1697)
    - Tanaka, Yayoi, 2003 (Box 130, Folder 1698)
    - Sethaputra, Sacha, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 1699)
    - Pitsuan, Surin/Navarat, Kannitha, 2001-2002 (Box 130, Folder 1700)
    - Smith, Craig, 1998 (Box 131, Folder 1701)
    - Sivaramakrishnan, K.C., 2000 (Box 131, Folder 1702)
    - Miscellaneous brochure and papers regarding education programs and philanthropy, circa 2000 (Box 131, Folder 1703)
    - Miscellaneous reports regarding human security, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 1704)
    - Vithayathil, Trina, 2002-2004 (Box 131, Folder 1705)
    - Witoelar, Erma, 1999 (Box 131, Folder 1706)
    - Wright, Dan, 1997-2003 (Box 131, Folder 1707)
    - Wright, Dan, 1999 (Box 131, Folder 1708)
    - Xue, Hua, 1999-2003 (Box 131, Folder 1709)
    - Xue, Hua, 1999-2001 (Box 131, Folder 1710)
    - Tanaka, Yayoi, 2000-2003 (Box 131, Folder 1711)
    - Phetkanha, Yui, 1998-1999 (Box 131, Folder 1712)
    - Xiaoqui, Yu, 1997-2003 (Box 131, Folder 1713)
    - Zhang Ye, 1998-2003 (Box 131, Folder 1714)
    - Zi, Zhongyun, 1999-2003 (Box 131, Folder 1715)
    - Vermilion, Mark, 1996 (Box 131, Folder 1716)
  - Philanthropic organizations and research institutions, 1995-2004; 4; 1.045 Cubic Feet About 2.75 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    This subseries documents Peter F. Geithner's involvement with various philanthropic organizations and research institutions following his retirement from the Ford Foundation in 1996. For the majority of these organizations, Geithner worked either as an advisor or as a board/committee member. Individual files were created to hold the records of specific organizations, and they generally contain correspondence, reports, and promotional material that concern a particular project, initiative, workshop, or meeting. Records regarding the Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF) show Geithner's role in advising the foundation on nonprofit management.
    Researchers should search the first two series of the collection in order to discover more substantial documentation of the majority of organizations featured within the subseries. However, the subseries does contain the collection's most extensive amount of records regarding Geithner's association with the Global Policy Exchange. These records concern the organization's efforts to bring cultural perspectives to policy decisions on issues of international security, anti-terrorism measures, and the West's relationship with Muslim-majority countries. Improved understandings of Islam and Muslim communities in Indonesia are heavily discussed.
    - Harvard University Ash Institute for Democratic Governance and Innovation, 2003 (Box 132, Folder 1717)
    - Harvard University Ash Institute for Democratic Governance and Innovation, 2003 (Box 132, Folder 1718)
    - Fund for Reconciliation and Development (FRD), 2002-2003 (Box 132, Folder 1719-1720)
    - Global Policy Exchange, 2003 (Box 132, Folder 1721)
    - Global Policy Exchange, 2002 (Box 132, Folder 1722)
    - Global Policy Exchange, 2001-2003 (Box 132, Folder 1723)
    - Global Policy Exchange, 2003 (Box 132, Folder 1724)
    - Global Policy Exchange, 2002-2003 (Box 132, Folder 1725)
    - Global Policy Exchange, 2002-2003 (Box 132, Folder 1726-1727)
    - Institute of Current World Affairs (ICWA) Finance Committee, 1999-2004 (Box 132, Folder 1728)
    - Institute of Current World Affairs (ICWA), circa 2003 (Box 133, Folder 1729)
    - Institute of Current World Affairs (ICWA) Board of Trustees, 1995-2003 (Box 133, Folder 1730)
    - Institute of Current World Affairs (ICWA) Board of Trustees, 2004 January 2 (Box 133, Folder 1731)
    - Institute of Current World Affairs (ICWA), 2000-2003 (Box 133, Folder 1732)
    - Institute of Current World Affairs (ICWA), 2003 (Box 133, Folder 1733)
    - Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF), 1997-2003 (Box 133, Folder 1734-1737)
    - Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF), 2000-2003 (Box 133, Folder 1738-1739)
    - Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF), 2001 (Box 133, Folder 1740)
    - Sasakawa Peace Foundation (SPF), 2002 September (Box 133, Folder 1741)
    - The Synergos Institute, 1999-2001 (Box 134, Folder 1742-1745)
    - U.S.-China Legal Cooperation Fund, 2003-2004 (Box 134, Folder 1746)
    - Temple University, 2003 (Box 134, Folder 1747)
    - U.S.-China Legal Cooperation Fund, 1999-2001 (Box 134, Folder 1748)
    - World Economic Forum (WEF), 2003 (Box 134, Folder 1749)
  - Reports, articles, and publications, 1983-2004; 5; 1.995 Cubic Feet About 5.25 LTR size Hollinger boxes
    This subseries consists primarily of reports, articles, newspapers clippings, books, newsletters, and promotional material. Peter F. Geithner may have acquired some of these publications in order to inform his or other individuals' outlook on a particular issue or topic. For instance, there is a significant amount of content regarding different China-related subjects. Other papers and publications were sent as drafts to Geithner for his review and/or revisions.
    Geithner participated in the writing and compilation of a few of the publications contained within the subseries. These publications originated from projects Geithner worked on after he retired from his post at the Ford Foundation. His consultancy appointments for Ford's Beijing, China and Hanoi, Vietnam Office produced two of the reports found in the subseries. There are also a number of files that document how the diaspora philanthropy volume for the Harvard University Global Equity Initiative (GEI) Diaspora Philanthropy Workshop (DPW) was put together and revised.
    In addition to various kinds of press and publications, the subseries includes a photograph of the Ford Foundation's New Delhi, India Office staff in 1985.
    - Survey Reports - Research Institutions, NGOs, and Philanthropy in Asia Pacific, 1994 (Box 134, Folder 1750-1751)
    - Survey Reports - Research Institutions, NGOs, and Philanthropy in Asia Pacific, 1994 (Box 134, Folder 1752)
    - NGO reports and promotional material, 1996-2004 (Box 135, Folder 1753-1755)
    - United Nations Economic and Social Commission for Asia and the Pacific (ESCAP) publications, 1995 (Box 135, Folder 1756)
    - Japan Foundation Center for Global Partnership (CGP) - Growth, Development, and Preservation Along the Ancient Silk Road: Creating Livable and Lasting Cities grant project, 1993-1997 (Box 135, Folder 1757-1758)
    - Group Action Planning for International Philanthropy (GAP) - Prospects for International Cooperation among Asian Foundations Mission Report, 1997 February (Box 135, Folder 1759)
    - Hopkins-Nanjing Center for Chinese and American Studies promotional material and reports, 2001-2003; File contains a DVD titled Hopkins-Nanjing Center. (Box 135, Folder 1760)
    - Hopkins-Nanjing Center DVD (Box 135, Folder 1760)
    - Ford Foundation - Crossing Borders: Revitalizing Area Studies, 1999 April (Box 135, Folder 1761)
    - Harvard University Diaspora Philanthropy Workshop (DPW) proceedings, 2003 (Box 135, Folder 1762)
    - Harvard University Diaspora Philanthropy Workshop (DPW) volume - Overview chapter draft, 2004 (Box 135, Folder 1763)
    - Harvard University Diaspora Philanthropy Workshop (DPW) volume papers - Drafts, 2003-2004 (Box 136, Folder 1764-1768)
    - Harvard University Diaspora Philanthropy Workshop (DPW) - Follow-up, 2001-2004 (Box 136, Folder 1769-1770)
    - Harvard University Diaspora Philanthropy Workshop (DPW), 2002-2004 (Box 137, Folder 1771-1775)
    - Various types of publications regarding China politics and international relations, 1987-1994 (Box 137, Folder 1776-1777)
    - The Ministry of Agriculture, China - Agriculture in China (1949-1989), 1989 July (Box 138, Folder 1778)
    - Book and article regarding China international trade and relations, 1994-1996 (Box 138, Folder 1779)
    - Publications regarding China village government and other China-related topics, 1983-1992 (Box 138, Folder 1780)
    - SOJOURN: Journal of Social Issues in Southeast Asia, Vol. 13, No. 2 - Families in Southeast Asia: Facing Fundamental Changes, 1998 October (Box 138, Folder 1781)
    - Papers regarding China, 1997 (Box 138, Folder 1782)
    - Papers regarding China economic development and international relations, 1992-1996 (Box 138, Folder 1783)
    - Tiananmen Square Two Years Later - How Did the Media Perform?: A Study of American Media Coverage of the Beijing Spring of 1989 - Draft, 1991 May 20 (Box 138, Folder 1784)
    - Assisting Legal Education and Research in China: A Report for the Ford Foundation, by Jerome A. Cohen and Nicholas C. Howson, 1991 (Box 138, Folder 1785)
    - Asia Society Asian Update - The Fourteenth Congress of the Chinese Communist Party, by David Bachman, 1992 November (Box 139, Folder 1786)
    - The Population Crisis Committee Country Study Series, No. 1 - China's Family Planning Program: Challenging the Myths, 1992 (Box 139, Folder 1787)
    - International Relations Studies in China: A Review of Ford Foundation's Past Grantmaking and Future Choices, 2001-2003 (Box 139, Folder 1788)
    - The 1990 Institute and Committee of 100 newsletters, 2003-2004 (Box 139, Folder 1789)
    - Articles regarding China balanced development, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1790)
    - Advisory Report to the Ford Foundation: Renovating Undergraduate Teaching of International Relations/Studies in Vietnam, 2003-2004 (Box 139, Folder 1791)
    - Alliance Bulletin, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1792)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1793)
    - The Ford Foundation's International Cooperation Program in Vietnam: A Report to the Ford Foundation by Peter F. Geithner, 2002 July 18 (Box 139, Folder 1794)
    - International Herald Tribune - China Will Change Its Own Way, by WeiWei Zhang, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1795)
    - Pieter Bottelier testimonies and papers regarding China, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1796)
    - Report and articles regarding India economy and government, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1797)
    - Jacques deLisle articles, 2003-2004 (Box 139, Folder 1798)
    - Global Giving Matters Newsletter, No. 17, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1799)
    - The Graying of the Middle Kingdom: The Demographics and Economics of Retirement Policy in China, 2004 April (Box 139, Folder 1800)
    - The Washington Quarterly articles regarding China politics, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1801)
    - Articles regarding U.S. in Iraq, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1802)
    - Indian Council for Research on International Economic Relations (ICRIER) Working Paper No. 123 - Health Insurance for the Poor In India, 2004 March (Box 139, Folder 1803)
    - With Fond Remembrance - Ford Foundation New Delhi Staff photograph, 1985 September (Box 139, Folder 1804)
    - Miscellaneous reports, 2004 (Box 139, Folder 1805)
- Ford Foundation, trips, meetings, and conferences, 1989-1997; 6; 1.33 Cubic Feet 3 LTR size Hollinger boxes and 1 Half-LTR size Hollinger box
  Series consists entirely of files Peter F. Geithner created to document business trips, meetings, and conferences during his last few years as Ford Foundation Regional Director of Asia Programs. The records were discovered in a filing cabinet. This distinct method of organization motivated the creation of a separate series to describe and house the materials during processing. Other materials were likely kept within this filing cabinet that could potentially provide more contextual information for the documents and this system of arrangement; however, those materials were impacted by mold growth and have been removed from the collection pending mold remediation.
  Files are mainly comprised of schedules, brochures, maps, invitation and attendee lists, correspondence, memos, notes, and travel reports. As mentioned in the Collection Scope and Contents note, Geithner would write travel reports to log his activities on business trips and would insert copies of them into the files he created to document particular trips.
  References to Geithner's approaching retirement from the Ford Foundation can be found within some of the materials. For example, there is an invitation to a farewell reception for Geithner at the Beijing Office in 1996 as well as a draft of the remarks Geithner planned to make at the event. A few of the files located towards the end of the series may actually originate from after Geithner's official retirement from Ford.
  - Shanghai and Beijing, China trip, 1994-1995 (Box 140, Folder 1806)
  - Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam trip, 1994-1995; Files contains a set of 11 still images and 5 photo negative strips. The images are photographs of different individuals and buildings Peter F. Geithner likely saw during his trip to Vietnam in March, 1995. Geithner is photographed in two of the images. The negatives are for the 11 Vietnam photographs. (Box 140, Folder 1807)
  - Indonesia trip, 1992-1995 (Box 140, Folder 1808)
  - Institute of Southeast Asia Studies (ISEAS) - Conference on New Asia Pacific Order, 1994-1995 (Box 140, Folder 1809)
  - Singapore trip, 1993-1995 (Box 140, Folder 1810)
  - Hong Kong trip, 1989-1995 (Box 140, Folder 1811)
  - London and Oxford, England trip, 1993-1995 (Box 140, Folder 1812)
  - Forum on Vietnam, Cambodia, and Laos Conference, 1995 (Box 140, Folder 1813)
  - Philippines trip, 1994-1995 (Box 140, Folder 1814)
  - Dhaka, Bangladesh trip, 1995 (Box 140, Folder 1815)
  - Council on Foundations Conference on Corporate Citizenship in Asia Pacific, 1995 (Box 140, Folder 1816-1817)
  - Vietnam Minister of Foreign Affairs Nguyen Manh Cam briefing, 1995 (Box 140, Folder 1818)
  - Chinese University Leaders Delegation, 1995 (Box 141, Folder 1819)
  - Harvard University Fairbank Center for East Asian Research - Different Roots, Differing Routes: An International Corporate Conference on China and India, 1995 (Box 141, Folder 1820)
  - Ditchley Foundation Conference - China After Deng: Policy Implications, 1995; File contains a set of 2 still images. They are photographs taken at the Ditchley Foundation Conference - China After Deng: Policy Implications in October 1995. Queen Elizabeth II of Great Britain is featured in one of the photographs. (Box 141, Folder 1821)
  - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations (NCUSCR) Conference- The Emergence of China Into the Global Community background readings, 1995 (Box 141, Folder 1822)
  - Vietnam International Relations Research and Training Delegation, 1995 (Box 141, Folder 1823)
  - China trip, 1994-1996 (Box 141, Folder 1824)
  - Japan Center for International Exchange (JCIE) - Asia Pacific Agenda Project (APAP) Tokyo Forum, 1995-1996 (Box 141, Folder 1825)
  - Hanoi, Vietnam trip, 1995 (Box 141, Folder 1826)
  - American Foreign Service Association (AFSA) Conference - Vietnam: Challenges and Opportunities, 1995-1996 (Box 141, Folder 1827)
  - India trip, 1995 (Box 141, Folder 1828)
  - Asia Programs Representatives' Meeting - Singapore, 1994-1995 (Box 141, Folder 1829)
  - Asia Programs Regional Meeting - Philippines, 1995-1996 (Box 141, Folder 1830)
  - World Bank/International Center for Not-for-Profit Law (ICNL) Workshop, 1995-1996 (Box 142, Folder 1831)
  - Council on Foundations - Joint Working Group on International Corporate Philanthropy meeting - San Francisco, CA, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 1832)
  - Tokyo, Japan trip, 1995-1996 (Box 142, Folder 1833)
  - Vietnam trip, 1995-1996 (Box 142, Folder 1834)
  - Thailand trip, 1994-1996 (Box 142, Folder 1835)
  - Dhaka, Bangladesh trip, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 1836)
  - Overseas Program Review and Board Meeting in Southern Africa, 1995 (Box 142, Folder 1837)
  - Beijing, China trip, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 1838)
  - Foreign Policy Research Institute (FPRI) Conference - Toward Reducing Sino-American Tensions, 1995-1997 (Box 142, Folder 1839-1840)
  - Asia Pacific Philanthropy Consortium (APPC) - Comparative Nonprofit Law Project Conference and Workshop for Legal Specialists, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 1841-1843)
  - Manila, Philippines trip, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 1844)
  - Tokyo, Japan trip, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 1845)
  - Beijing, China trip, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 1846)
  - Columbia University The American Assembly - China-U.S. Relations in the Twenty-First Century: Fostering Cooperation, Preventing Conflict, 1996 (Box 143, Folder 1847)
  - Washington D.C. trip, 1996 (Box 143, Folder 1848)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia (UBCHEA) Board of Trustees dinner and reception, 1996 (Box 143, Folder 1849)
  - Trilateral Project meeting - Beijing, China, 1996 (Box 143, Folder 1850)
  - Harvard Institute for International Development (HIID)/Center for International Affairs (CIFA) Conference on India's Economic Reforms, 1996 (Box 143, Folder 1851-1852)